BRADLEY SPICLIN

Tel: 0402524452 **Email:** bradleyspiclin@gmail.com **LinkedIn:** <u>www.linkedin.com/in/bradley-spiclin</u>

Career Profile

As a resolute and motivated second-year Bachelor of Information Technology student majoring in Applications Development, I possess a strong skill set in interpersonal communication and management enabling me to excel in a dynamic work environment while interacting with clients, staff, and stakeholders. With a rich background in customer service and community safety, I have experience collaborating with others and utilizing critical thinking skills to successfully manage complex situations. I am an enthusiastic about information technology with a strong drive for problem-solving. As a lifelong learner, I strive to enhance my technical expertise and knowledge in pursuit of my ultimate career goal of becoming a Software Engineer.

Education

03/2022 – Current Bachelor of Information Technology

Deakin University, Waurn Ponds

Minor: Programming

Minor: Game Design

05/2021 – 10/2021 Certificate IV in Information Technology

The Gordon Institute of TAFE, Geelong

- Programming in C# and Java
- Networking
- Cybersecurity
- Workplace health and safety

Technical Skills

Programming Languages

• C#, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, Python, Bash, C++

Platforms and Technologies

Visual Studio, VS Code, Microsoft Azure, GitHub, Jenkins, Office 365

University Projects

05/2022 Data Analytics of Twitter Keywords (Group project)

- Collaborated with group members to crawl data using Twitter API, writing data to JSON files, and performing detailed analytics using Jupiter Notebook (Python).
- Received a High Distinction.

04/2022 Covid-19 Data Analytics Project (Individual project)

- Comparative analysis of Covid-19 data using Jupiter Notebook, using imported realworld data from CSV file.
- Received a High Distinction.

Employment History

2013 – Current Department of Justice and Community Safety

Corrections Victoria

- Enforcing and maintaining strict policy and procedure to ensure the safe daily operation of a prison environment.
- Practicing and adhering to current legislation whilst controlling and solving complex situations.
- Managing a prisoner caseload, meeting with, and establishing a document to support and encourage goals, promoting a positive outlook and attempting to reduce recidivism.
- Addressing offending behavior through constant static and dynamic security.
- Continuous training and development to ensure current practices and maintained.

2006 – 2013 Sales Assistant

JB-HI-FI, Geelong

- Deliver sound advice to customers on current products including computers, audio visual equipment and various other technologies.
- Excelling in customer service by establishing a returning customer base through unparalleled service and customer satisfaction.
- Responding to customers' phone and email enquiries, determining their needs, and contributing to product recommendations.

Professional Memberships

10/2022 - Current Member

Australian Computer Society

Professional Development

02/2023 Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

Issued by Microsoft

02/2023 C#/.NET 50 Essential Interview Questions (Junior Level)

Udemy.com

10/2022 C# Tutorial – Full Course for Beginners

free Code Camp.org

05/2022 Certified Secure Computer User

EC-Council

Extra-curricular Activities

09/2022 – 10/2022 Volunteer Program

School of Information Technology Learning Support Help Hub, Deakin University

- Supplied one-on-one mentoring and assistance to students in the Introduction to Programming unit.
- Effectively communicated with students from non-English speaking backgrounds and assisted in developing their critical thinking skills in creative ways.

Referees